Thomas Maher

Norwalk, CT 06851 **T**: 203-246-5155

E: t.maher621@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://thomas-maher-portfolio.herokuapp.com/ **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomas-maher-0b3615217/

GitHub: https://github.com/trm621

Technical Skills:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Ruby on Rails
- Python
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- Server-Side/Third-Party APIs
- Object Oriented Programming
- React
- MySQL
- NoSQL

Projects:

Trail Talk

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/trm621/national-park-social-app

Deployed Site: https://pacific-shelf-58337.herokuapp.com/

A full MERN stack social media application on which users can create an account, create text posts, and add other users as friends. The goal of the site is to get in touch with people around the world to discuss their favorite national parks and give suggestions as to where park lovers might want to make their next trip.

- Worked on front end and back end along with designing the look of the app.
- MERN Stack: React front End, MongoDB database and Node.js/ Express.js server and API
- Built with HTML / CSS / JS

Binge Buddy

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/trm621/movie-night-generator/
Deployed Site: https://trm621.github.io/movie-night-generator/

An application built for the purpose of randomly selecting a dinner and movie pairing for movie night, date night, or a party.

- Built JavaScript functionality and implemented the Tasty API into the code.
- Utilizes the third-party Tasty and IMDB APIs.
- Built with HTML / CSS / JS.

ReadMe Generator

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/trm621/readme-buddy

Video of Site in use:

https://drive.google.com/file/d/16rbgJeUkvjxtn3FyfM9znjDt2WeErmDd/view?usp=sharing

A Node application in which a user can input information through the command line to generate a professional ReadMe file for their project.

- Created application on my own.
- Utilizes Node and the Inquirer package to run through the command line.
- Built with JS.

Work Experience:

Video Editor, Sound Mixer | Freelance

September 2011 – Present

• Filmed and edited trailers for the Ithaca College Macabre Theater Ensemble's college productions.

Magazine Editor | Stillwater Magazine, Ithaca College | Ithaca, NY September 2014 – May 2015

- Wrote and edited stories for Stillwater Magazine.
- Coordinated and emceed events.

Summer Intern | Games.com | New York, NY June 2012 – August 2012

• Aided in rebuilding site for relaunch, including writing site descriptions, editing images, creating blog posts.

Summer Intern | AOL, Travel | New York, NY June 2010 – August 2010

 Aided in building site for launch, including testing new webpage creation engine, compiling data in Excel.

Education:

Ithaca College | Ithaca, NY September 2011 - May 2015 Bachelors in Writing, Minor in English

University of Connecticut School of Engineering | Coding Bootcamp | Stoors, CT September 2021 - March 2022 Certificate of Training as Full-Stack Web Developer